That's a stone, Charlie. A brown stone.
是块石头  查理  褐色的大石头
It's very very amazing and special.
这石头太神奇了
Is it a very special stone from the garden?
是在园子里发现的吗
No, Lola. This stone is ancient.
不是  劳拉  这是块沉睡已久的古石
It's really, really, really old.
它的历史非常非常之久
Did it come from Granny's garden?
它之前是在奶奶的园子里吗
Granny's very very old. She's older than even 25.
奶奶岁数已经很大了  她已经25啦
It's much much older than Granny and Grandpa.
这块石头比爷爷奶奶还大呢
It's not just a stone.
它不能叫石头
This is actual fossil.
应该是块化石
It's like a skeleton of an animal that lived a very long time ago.
就像动物的骨骼  经过亿万年慢慢石化而来
at the same time as the dinosaurs!
或许是恐龙时期留下的呢
It looks all whirly! Like a curly slide!
它形似陀螺  像弯来绕去的大蛇滑梯